A Guide to the International Education Board records, Albert R. Mann and Harry Luman Russell logs index FA769
Rockefeller Archive Center
International Education Board records, Albert R. Mann and Harry Luman Russell logs index
1924-1927
Rockefeller Archive Center
International Education Board
Mann, Albert R
Russell, Harold L
FA769
3 Cubic Feet 9 boxes; 5x8x12 inches each.
Albert R. Mann
Albert R. Mann (1880-1947) studied agriculture at Cornell University, and was graduated in 1904. Mann was appointed Assistant Professor in 1908 at Cornell, Secretary-Editor-Registrar in 1908, Professor of Rural Social Organization in 1915, Acting Dean in 1916, Dean in 1917, and finally Provost in 1931.
From 1924-1926 Mann directed the International Education Board's (IEB) program of agricultural education and rehabilitation in Europe. Mann returned to Cornell in 1926, but the IEB program continued by his associate, C. B. Hutchison until conclusion in 1928.
In 1936 the General Education Board (GEB) engaged Mann to survey the problems of agricultural colleges in the southern United States, and produced the report "Rural Economic and Social Studies in Southern Institutions". Mann was then appointed Vice President and Director of the GEB in 1937. After retiring from the GEB in 1946, Mann then joined the Natural Sciences Division of the Rockefeller Foundation on a part-time basis, to lead the agricultural program.
In the winter of 1946-1947, Mann travelled to Germany to visit universities and research institutions interview former fellows and professors the Foundation had contacts with before World War II, and appraise the educational needs of those centers. Mann died on February 21, 1947 in New York, while returning from Germany. For more information on Mann's career, see the Rockefeller Foundation Trustees Bulletin, March 1947, pages 1-8.
Harry Luman Russell
Harry Luman Russell (1866-1954) was an American bacteriologist and educator. Russell was graduated from the University of Wisconsin in 1884, received an M.S. from Wisconsin in 1890, and a Ph.D. from Johns Hopkins in 1892. Russell then became a Professor at the University of Wisconsin. In 1903 Russell was made Director of the Wisconsin State Hygienic Laboratory, and became Dean of the University of Wisconsin's College of Agriculture in 1907. Russell was also a charter member of the American Society for Microbiology, and was named President in 1908. In 1925 Russell was commissioned by the International Education Board (IEB) to travel through Asia, and survey the scientific and agricultural education needs in Japan, China, the Philippines, Siam, Java, Australia, and New Zealand.
General
The index provides excerpts and indexing to Albert R. Mann's logs during his term as the International Education Board's Director of Agricultural Education for Europe from 1924-1927, and to Harry Luman Russell's logs during his IEB commissioned trip through Asia from 1925-1926.
Related Materials
The Mann and Russell logs (diaries) are found in the Rockefeller Foundation records, officers' diaries, RG 12, M-R (FA393).
Arrangement
The index is arranged alphabetically.
Scope and Contents
The index includes headings for names, subjects, and places. Subjects are subdivided geographically. Subject subdivisions other then geographic are considered compound titles, following the main group; for example: Botany; Botany-Anatomy; Botany-Medical, etc. Headings appear on the left tabs, subdivisions on the center tabs, and sub-subdivisions on the right tabs.
Common abbreviations include: ARM = Albert R. Mann; CBH = C.B. Hutchison (assistant to Mann); CIC = Committee on Intellectual Cooperation, League of Nations; CS = Czechoslovakia; IEB = International Education Board; IIA = International Institute of Agriculture, Rome; and HLR = Harry Luman Russell.
Citations to the Mann and Russell logs are found on the right edge of the index cards, by the diarist's name, log number, page number, and date. For instance: "Mann Log 1: 76-77, (9/22/24)" indicates Mann's log #1, pages 76-77, dated September 22, 1924.
Related Materials
See also the logs of Albert R. Mann and Harry Luman Russell, found in the Rockefeller Foundation records, officers' diaries, RG 12, M-R (FA393), boxes 284-288 and 419-420.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research.
Agriculture -- Asia.; Agriculture; Science -- Biological and Medical
- Explanations, 1924-1927 (Box 1)
- A - Abbreviations, 1924-1927 (Box 1)
- Agricultural Chemistry, 1924-1927 (Box 1)
- Agricultural Colleges, 1924-1927 (Box 1)
- Agricultural Colonization, 1924-1927 (Box 1)
- Agricultural Credit, 1924-1927 (Box 1)
- Agricultural Economics, 1924-1927 (Box 1)
- Agricultural Education, 1924-1927 (Box 1)
- Agricultural Engineering, 1924-1927 (Box 1)
- Agricultural Exhibitions, 1924-1927 (Box 1)
- Agricultural Experiment Stations, 1924-1927 (Box 1)
- Agricultural Law and Legislation, 1924-1927 (Box 2)
- Agricultural Research, 1924-1927 (Box 2)
- Agricultural Schools, 1924-1927 (Box 2)
- Agricultural Societies, 1924-1927 (Box 2)
- Agricultural Statistics, 1924-1927 (Box 2)
- Agriculture, 1924-1927 (Box 2)
- Agronomy, 1924-1927 (Box 2)
- Anatomy, 1924-1927 (Box 2)
- Animal Husbandry, 1924-1927 (Box 2)
- Animal Pathology, 1924-1927 (Box 2)
- Apiculture, 1924-1927 (Box 2)
- Archaeology, 1924-1927 (Box 2)
- Astronomy, 1924-1927 (Box 2)
- Australia, 1924-1927 (Box 2)
- Austria, 1924-1927 (Box 2)
- Aviculture, 1924-1927 (Box 2)
- Bacteriology, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Banks and Banking, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Belgium, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Biological Chemistry, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Biological Physics, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Biology, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Biometry, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Botanical Gardens, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Botany, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Botany: Anatomy, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Botany: Medical, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Botany: Physiology, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Boys and Girls Clubs, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Brewing, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Bulgaria, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- C.R.B. Education Foundation, Inc., 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Cave Industry, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Census, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Chemistry, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Chemistry: Physical and Theoretical, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Chemistry: Technical, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- China, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Cooperation, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Cytology, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Czechoslovakia, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Dairy Associations, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
- Dairy Industry, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Dale, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Demonstration Work, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Denmark, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Dry Farming, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Ecology, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Economic, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Education, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Education: Adult, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Egg Trade, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Electric Service: Rural, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Engineering, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- England, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Entomology, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Estonia, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Extension Service, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Farm Bookkeeping, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Farm Buildings, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Farm Labor, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Farm Life, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Farm Machinery, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Farm Management, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Farm Surveys, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Farm Tours, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Feeding and Feeding Stuffs, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Fertilizers, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Finland, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Fish Culture, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
- Fisheries, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Floriculture, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Foodstuffs, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Forest Experiment Stations, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Forest Products, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Forestry, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Forestry Colleges, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Forestry Research, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Forestry Schools, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Forestry Societies, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Foundations, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- France, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Gardening, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Genetics, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Geodesy, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Geology, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Germany, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Gjuric, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Gordon, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Graduate Instruction, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Grain Elevators, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Greenhouses, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Guerrazzi, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Hall, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Hawaii, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Hennet, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Histology, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Holland, 1924-1927 (Box 5)
- Home and Education, 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- Home Economics, 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- Horticulture, 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- Hotels, 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- Hungary, 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- Ibos, 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- Industry, 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- Insurance, 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- International Education Board, 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- International Institute of Agriculture, 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- Irrigation Drainage and Water Power, 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- Italy, 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- Japan, 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- Java, 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- Jugo-Slavia (Yugoslavia), 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- Kiessling, 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- Korsmo, 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- Labor and Laboring Classes, 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- Land, 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- Land Tenure, 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- Larsen, 1924-1927 (Box 6)
- League of Nations, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Libraries, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Lithuania, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Logs, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- MAC and MC, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Malaria, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Mann, Albert R., 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Marine Biology, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Marketing, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Marshlands, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Mathematics, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Medical, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Metabolism, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Metrology, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Micro-organisms, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Mineralogy, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Morphology, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Museums, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Mycology, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- National, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- New Zealand, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Norway, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Nutrition, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Ornithology, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Parasitology, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Pastures and Meadows, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Philippine Islands, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Physics, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Physiology, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Plant Breeding, 1924-1927 (Box 7)
- Plant Cells and Tissues, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Plant Ecology, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Plant Pathology, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Plants: Nutrition, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Poland, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Pomology, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Poultry Husbandry, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Psychology, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Railroads, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Reclamation of land, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Rockefeller, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Rumania, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Russia, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Russian and Ukrainian Refugees, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Russian and Ukrainian Refugees -- Zemgor, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Scholarships and Fellowships, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- School Gardens, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Science, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Scotland, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Seed Testing and Control, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Seed Trade, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Sericulture, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Serology, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Serpieri, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Silage, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Social Services, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Sociology, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Soil Chemistry, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Soil Geology, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
- Soil Science, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Soil Surveys, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Soils, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Spain, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Stranski, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Sumatra, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Sweden, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Switzerland, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Taxation, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Tillyard, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Tropical Agriculture, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Tropical Diseases, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Tropical Forestry, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- United States, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Variety Tests, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Vegetable Gardening, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Veterinary Education, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Veterinary Service, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Village, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Viticulture and Wine-making, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Vocational Education, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Wages, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Wales, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Weeds, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Women as Farm Laborers, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Women in Agricultural Institutions, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Yagi, 1924-1927 (Box 9)
- Zoology, 1924-1927 (Box 9)